<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Personal Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.svohra.com/categories/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 20:22:37 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.svohra.com/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Knative</title>
      <link>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/knative/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 20:22:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/knative/</guid>
      <description>Knative #  Serving #  Label networking.knative.dev/visibility: cluster-local marks a Knative Service as private and accesible only ClusterIP. The default is to make the Knative Service publically accessible.
Job https://github.com/knative/serving/releases/download/latest/serving-default-domain.yaml updates -n knative-serving cm/config-domain to add a default domain such as 34.145.71.17.sslip.io</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K8s Debugging</title>
      <link>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/k8s-debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 21:20:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/k8s-debugging/</guid>
      <description>Get an ubuntu shell on a K8s cluster #  Run
kubectl run my-temp-shell --rm -i --tty --image ubuntu -- bash Ref</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPi with K3S with Knative</title>
      <link>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/raspberry-pi-k3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 20:50:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/raspberry-pi-k3s/</guid>
      <description>The process #  Use Ubuntu Server 64 bit OS #  The Rasberry Pi OS is 32 bit and wont work for Envoy which only has arm64 images available.
Install OS #   Download the Ubuntu OS, extract the zip file Install it to the SD Card Instructions  diskutil list # Get disk# diskutil unmountDisk /dev/diskN sudo dd bs=1m if=path_of_your_image.img of=/dev/rdiskN; sync sudo diskutil eject /dev/rdiskN replacing N with the disk number</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a K8s CRD</title>
      <link>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/create-k8s-crd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 14:45:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/create-k8s-crd/</guid>
      <description>Create a K8s CRD #  This summarizes the tutorial referenced below &amp;amp; Knative Controllers as a quick review
Scafold the new CRD #  kubebuilder create api --group batch --version v1 --kind CronJob
Define The Object #  Look under {apis|api/v1}/{groupName}/{objectName}_types.go contains K8s Object.Spec and Object.Status
Update the Spec &amp;amp; Status sections
Add the Business Logic #  Implement the logic to convert desired state defined in the spec to the actual state reflected in the status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inclusive Leadership</title>
      <link>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/diversity-inclusion/inclusive-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 18:12:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/diversity-inclusion/inclusive-leadership/</guid>
      <description>These are my notes from session on Inclusive Leadership at VMware
Diversity #   visible traits and invisible traits/dimensions of our identity (eg. religion)  URMs #  minorities - black, latam, american indians, native alaskans, pacific islanders /hawaiaans  URGs #  groups  Equity #  distribution of resources to address systemic barriers and support equal outcomes vs. equality is everyone gets the same thing (eg. notebook + pen vs laptops for devs, etc) equal is not equitable (meat to a room that includes vegetarians)  Inclusion #   Cognizance bias is a achillles heel Humility - i am biased but want to improve Empathy - prespective taking Courage talking about imperfections takes risk taking Commitment staying the course is hard Curiosity Cultural Intelligence Collaboration  In Groups #   set the rules/norms in a culture often unaware of their privilege  Out Groups #   work hard to fit in less power  Pschological Safety #   Amy Edmonson Sense of confidence that the team will not embarass, reject or punish someone for speaking up Shared beleif that the team is safe for interpersonal risk taking Notice when you&amp;rsquo;re contributing to in-group/out-group behaviours  Create Pysch safety #   encourage conversational turn-taking be empathetic and socially sensitve  Micro aggressions #   they are suble discrimination that reflects painful stereotypes, practices, policies and world views  analogy of mosquito bites  1 bite is annoying constant biting over a long period of time is debilitating     admit they exist ask difficult questions show peers that it is unacceptable - call them out microaffirmations can counter microaggessions recognize that microagressions reflect painful, deeply embedded stereotypes, practices, policies, and worldviews if bias is &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rdquo;; microaggressions are the &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo;  Covering #   hiding a unfavored trait/identity to fit in appearance based affiliation based emotional tax - the state of being on guard  intersectionality #  no one is defined by a single category  Privilege #   system advantage or privileged isnt so much about what you have, but what you dont have to think about  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LeadDev Diversity &amp; Inclusion</title>
      <link>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/diversity-inclusion/leaddev/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 18:12:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/diversity-inclusion/leaddev/</guid>
      <description>These are my notes from a session on Diversity &amp;amp; Inclusion at LeadDev
What matters !! #  Impact matters much more than intention
 essentially not having ill intension is not sufficient one has to be accountable for the impact of one&amp;rsquo;s actions this is more significant in situations when one party has a position of privilege or authority  In such cases
 Acknowledge the mistake Make a committment to change Be accountable  Simple definitions #   Privilege = Access Underrepresented = It is a matter of #s Marginalized = Treatment Inclusion !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CKAD Exam Preparation</title>
      <link>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/ckad-exam-prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 20:50:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/ckad-exam-prep/</guid>
      <description>The process #  Study #  Took Mumshad&amp;rsquo;s super popular CKAD preparation course. It introduced the relevant kubernetes concepts and the labs at the end of each section were great for reinforcing the material. At $20 the course was a steal 🔥🔥🔥. This was the only resource I used and I passed the exam 🎉.
Practice #  From reading about the exam online and from the mock exams in Mumshad&amp;rsquo;s course, I realized that the exam is not hard but you have to be fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CKAD Notes</title>
      <link>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/ckad-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 18:15:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/ckad-notes/</guid>
      <description>Sparse CKAD Notes #  Node #  Runs the containers deployed on K8s. It is the worker
Kubelet #  Agent running on the node that monitors health of pods and running pods on the container runtime
Container Runtime #  Engine that runs the containers
Master #  Handles all requests and is the brains that orchestrates work on the workers
API Server #  Receives all incoming API requests and is the frontend to K8s cluster</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/diversity-inclusion/resource-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 18:30:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/diversity-inclusion/resource-list/</guid>
      <description>These are a list of resources that addressing diversity and inclusion that were recommended to me and resources that I found helpful to increase my awareness.
TODO #   Ijeoma recommends  So You Want to Talk About Race The Bamboo ceiling (Asians in the tech sector) Anything by Michelle Alexander Dr Kindal Crenshaw on Intersectionality Race mediation workboooks   Denise Yu recommends  Tatiana Mac - Priviledge defines performance    Between the World and Me by Ta-Nehisi Coates #  Book</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Real - Ijeoma Oluo</title>
      <link>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/diversity-inclusion/getting-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 19:59:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/diversity-inclusion/getting-real/</guid>
      <description>Getting Real #  These were some notes from a session by Ijeoma organized at VMware
Alyship #   is defined in the moment, not a badge that can be worn the stance taken in the moment by a person, as seen from the perspective of the person who is expected to benefit from it  Referrals #   average white person knows less than &amp;lt; 1 black person, this perpetuates the status quo and doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow for more diversity  Responsibility #   the system is broken, the onus to correct the system is on the leaders and folks in the position of priviledge it isn&amp;rsquo;t on the folks that are victimized, they may be struggling to just get by when asking someone who is under represented for knowledge/info, ask for permission first, recognize its a favor and not an obligation for the person to provide the info take responsibility for educating yourself, don&amp;rsquo;t expect others to educate you, it isn&amp;rsquo;t their job  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking</title>
      <link>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 19:16:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/networking/</guid>
      <description>Debugging #  Monitor Sockets #  ss
 Get all outbound TCP connections to a HOST:PORT combination ss -it | grep SOME_PORT_NUMBER  Monitor TCP Connections #  netstat
  Get all TCP connections on a host netstat -t
 Observe the Send-Q and Recv-Q to see how many bytes are waiting to be read/written -o adds timer info and connection state    Get Summary, good starting point to see if there are dropped packets netstat -s</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drives, Volumes, Disks &amp; Partitions</title>
      <link>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/drives-volumes-disks-partitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 14:45:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/drives-volumes-disks-partitions/</guid>
      <description>Drives, Volumes, Disks &amp;amp; Partitions #  Drive #  Physical storage device such as a hard disk, solid-state disk, removable USB flash drive etc. In Unix-like operating systems devices are represented by special file system objects called device nodes which are visible under the /dev directory
Partions #  A physical storage device can be divided into multiple logical storage units known as partitions.
Volume #  The term volume in Linux is related to the Logical Volume Manager (LVM), which can be used to manage mass storage devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shell Commands</title>
      <link>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/cmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 09:25:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.svohra.com/posts/software/cmd/</guid>
      <description>General #    switch user su some-user-name
  execute previous command !!
  List file system mounts findmnt
  Filter results awk &#39;/search_pattern/ {print $2 $1}&#39;
 $1 refers to column 1 &amp;amp; $2 refers to column 2, starting from index 0    Search #    Find File find path_to_search -name &amp;quot;*.txt&amp;quot; 
 -not to inverse results -maxdepth some_int to limit depth of search -size +1M find files larger than 1 MB -type f|d find files or directories `-exec grep -n -i &amp;ldquo;foo&amp;rdquo;    Grep grep -i &amp;quot;string_to_be_searched&amp;quot; path_to_search</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
